# TECHNICAL SKILLS

React.js, Java, Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Express, RESTful API, JSON, Django, Bootstrap, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, VS Code, Postman, MySQL Workbench, GitHub

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

#### Job Trackr

An app designed to organize your job searching experience: Balsamiq, React, MongoDB, JSON, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, Material-UI

- Built an application using React that allows users to organize and keep track of attributes of a job search.
- Created a database using APIs that stores multiple users and their respective job prospects.
- Created forms and implemented design elements using Bootstrap, CSS, and Material-UI to deliver a sleek and simple user interface.

#### Coding Dojo Merchandise Store

On-brand Coding Dojo eCommerce site: React, Redux, MongoDB, JSON, CSS, Bootstrap

- Created a fast and simple single-page application using React that allows users to easily browse our online merchandise store.
- Managed application states such as shopping carts and checkout pages with Redux giving users a seamless shopping experience.
- Managed user accounts and store inventories with MongoDB and JSON database management system allowing site administrators to easily maintain the website.
- Designed a responsive, user-friendly UI using CSS and Bootstrap templates to create a clean user experience.

## **Amazon Clone**

Amazon eCommerce site replica: React, CSS, BEM, Google Firebase

- Designed a single-page application using React to replicate the Amazon eCommerce website's functionality and aesthetics.
- Implemented a login/registration component, shopping cart management system using Firebase allowing users to purchase merchandise.
- Styled the Amazon aesthetics using CSS and BEM methodology for reusable/easily-modifiable code.

## Sous Chef Recipe-Finder

A recipe-finder for products currently in your pantry/refrigerator: Python, Django, MySQL, Regex, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

- Implemented login/registration system using MySQL, RegEx patterns, Bcrypt to personalize user experience and allow proper user authentications.
- Utilized Django's MTV architecture and its one-to-many and many-to-many relationships to allow users to create, update, delete, and favorite recipes.
- Created a clean user interface with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap to provide a simple user experience for the user.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

COX Communications - Graphic Designer - 2016-2020

• Designed print, web, and social media collaterals using Adobe Creative Suite to enhance professional presence for company events promoting Gigabit Speeds and Smart Home integrations.

CEC Print Solutions - Print Technician - 2014-2015

- Assisted in daily printing processes using offset printing plates and digital printing technologies to provide print materials for local clients.
- Utilized Guillotine Paper Cutter to cut prints to specifications, boxed prints, and managed storage system using pallet jacks.

#### **EDUCATION**

Coding Dojo Bootcamp - Full-Stack Developer Certification 2020-2021

- MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), Java, Python full stack development
  California State University East Bay BA Graphic Design 2006-2010
  - Proficiency in Print, Web Design utilizing Adobe Creative Suite applications